<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
  <responseDate>2023-03-15T16:13:11Z</responseDate>
  <request verb="Identify">https://api.aiscr.cz/oai</request>
  <Identify>
    <repositoryName>Archaeological Map of the Czech Republic (AMCR)</repositoryName>
    <baseURL>https://api.aiscr.cz/oai</baseURL>
    <protocolVersion>2.0</protocolVersion>
    <adminEmail>info@amapa.cz</adminEmail>
    <earliestDatestamp>1990-01-01</earliestDatestamp>
    <deletedRecord>persistent</deletedRecord>
    <granularity>YYYY-MM-DDThh:mm:ssZ</granularity>
    <description>
      <rightsManifest xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/rights/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/rights/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/rightsManifest.xsd" appliesTo="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/entity#metadata">
        <rights>
          <rightsReference ref="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/rdf"/>
        </rights>
      </rightsManifest>
    </description>
    <description>
      <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
        <dc:title xml:lang="cs">Archeologická mapa České Republiky (AMČR)</dc:title>
        <dc:title xml:lang="en">Archaeological Map of the Czech Republic (AMCR)</dc:title>
        <dc:creator xml:lang="cs">Archeologický ústav AV ČR, Praha, v.v.i.</dc:creator>
        <dc:creator xml:lang="en">Institute of Archaeology of the Czech Academy of Sciences, Prague</dc:creator>
        <dc:creator xml:lang="cs">Archeologický ústav AV ČR, Brno, v.v.i.</dc:creator>
        <dc:creator xml:lang="en">Institute of Archaeology of the Czech Academy of Sciences, Brno</dc:creator>
        <dc:publisher xml:lang="cs">Archeologický informační systém České republiky (AIS CR)</dc:publisher>
        <dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Archaeological Information System of the Czech Republic (AIS CR)</dc:publisher>
        <dc:identifier>https://api.aiscr.cz/</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>version 2.0.0</dc:identifier>
        <dc:source>https://amcr-info.aiscr.cz/</dc:source>
        <dc:relation>http://www.aiscr.cz/</dc:relation>
        <dc:description xml:lang="cs">Archeologická mapa České republiky (AMČR) je informační systém pro sběr, správu a prezentaci dat o archeologických výzkumech, nálezech a lokalitách na území ČR. Obsažená data popisují desetitisíce archeologických výzkumů a jejich konkrétních výsledků. Zahrnují informace o vedoucích výzkumu, o tom, kdy výzkum probíhal, o jeho lokalizaci i to, jaké nálezy a z jakého období výzkum zjistil. Většina záznamů je napojena na digitálních repozitář dokumentace a bibliografický katalog. AMČR je určena profesionálním archeologům, odborníkům z blízkých oborů, studentům i zájemcům z širší veřejnosti, jimž nabízí možnost efektivně pracovat s poznatky získanými generacemi archeologů v naší zemi. Je provozována Archeologickými ústavy AV ČR v Praze a Brně. AMČR je páteřní informační systém české archeologie, na který navazují účelová rozšíření ve formě dolňujících modulů. AMČR je nejdůležitější součástí širší infrastruktury Archeologický informační systém České republiky (AIS CR), která je zapsána na Cestovní mapě velkých infrastruktur pro výzkum, experimentální vývoj a innovace, schválené Vládou ČR.</dc:description>
        <dc:description xml:lang="en">Archaeological Map of the Czech Republic (AMCR) is an information system for the collection, management and presentation of data on archaeological fieldwork, finds and sites in the Czech Republic. The contained data describe tens of thousands of archaeological fieldwork and their results. They include information about the leaders of the research, when the research took place, its location and what finds and from what period the research found. Most records are linked to a digital repository of documentation and bibliographic catalogue. The AMCR is aimed at professional archaeologists, specialists in related fields, students and interested members of the general public, offering them the opportunity to work effectively with the knowledge gained by generations of archaeologists in the country. It is operated by the Institutes of Archaeological of the Czech Academy of Sciences in Prague and Brno. The AMCR is the backbone information system of Czech archaeology, which is followed by purpose-built extensions in the form of downstream modules. The AMCR is the most important part of the wider infrastructure Archaeological Information System of the Czech Republic (AIS CR), which is listed on the Roadmap of Large Infrastructures for Research, Experimental Development and Innovation, approved by the Government of the Czech Republic.</dc:description>
        <dc:description xml:lang="cs">Pro jednoznačné označení záznamů jsou užívány identifikátory obsažené v polích "ident_cely" společně se základní doménou "https://api.aiscr.cz/id/". Identifikátor je tak v argumentech vždy předáván v podobě "https://api.aiscr.cz/id/[ident_cely]" (např. "https://api.aiscr.cz/id/C-201912345"). Při přístupu v anonymním režimu je zobrazována pouze část záznamů. Při užití autentizačních údajů uživatelského účtu v AMČR je zohledňována přístupnost záznamu pro konkrétního uživatele. Plný obsah databáze je dostupný pouze odpovědným archivářům a administrátorům.</dc:description>
        <dc:description xml:lang="en">The identifiers contained in the "ident_cely" fields together with the base domain "https://api.aiscr.cz/id/" are used to uniquely identify records. Thus, the identifier is always passed in arguments in the form "https://api.aiscr.cz/id/[ident_cely]" (e.g. "https://api.aiscr.cz/id/C-201912345"). When accessing in anonymous mode, only a part of the records is displayed. When using authentication data of the user account in AMCR, the accessibility of the record for a specific user is taken into account. The full content of the database is available only to responsible archivists and administrators.</dc:description>
        <dc:description>https://amcr-info.aiscr.cz/help/</dc:description>
        <dc:language>cs</dc:language>
        <dc:language>en</dc:language>
      </oai_dc:dc>
    </description>
  </Identify>
</OAI-PMH>
